LESLIE BOOK

- 443-800-5595
- lesliek.book@gmail.com
- Nottingham, MD 21236

SKILLS

- Technical troubleshooting
- Wireless networking
- Documentation writing
- Equipment configuration
- Network security
- Hardware installation
- Implement hardware solutions
- Configure equipment
- Manage user access
- Task prioritizing
- Creative thinking

WEBSITES

LinkedIn - linkedin.com/in/lesliebook

GitHub profile - github.com/leskbook

Portfolio

- leskbook.github.io/homework2Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Talented Lead Network Engineer bringing advanced abilities in handling networking design and management requirements in large, fast-paced environments. Prepares standard operating and configuration procedures to deliver consistent support and reliable network performance. Maintains strict security standards through hardware, software, and user access controls. Highly organized while bringing strengths in handling work independently and solving routine problems without oversight. Offering expertise in design, automation, and ability to quickly learn new processes.

EXPERIENCE

LEAD NETWORK ENGINEER

CareFirst BlueCross & BlueShield

Baltimore, MD

September 2012 - Current

Responsible for developing, implementing, and maintaining the CareFirst Blue Cross & Blue Shield network infrastructure, with an extensive knowledge of capacity planning. Configure network infrastructure, daily monitoring of network system to ensure adherence to security controls, maximum performance levels and customer SLA's. Lead engineer in future design and infrastructure road map. Participating in the development and implementation of information security policy, standards, guidelines, and procedures to ensure ongoing maintenance of information security and protection. Lead engineer on multiple security remediation initiatives across the enterprise. Lead engineer on complex wireless infrastructure initiative impacting entire enterprise. Lead engineer on multiple remote site forklift switch upgrades. This included design, build of materials and implementation. Lead engineer responsible for maintaining Windows and Linux based network management appliances.

- Monitored network performance to identify and correct routin problems and serious concerns.
- Responded promptly to out-of-hours emergencies to manage failures affecting critical business systems.
- Handled service calls submitted to help desk to troubleshoot, diagnose, and resolve various network issues.
- Designed and implemented network solutions in line with healthcare industry standards and company requirements.
- Assessed need for network updates and reconfigurations and implemented strategies to meet demands.

- Managed networking needs across 22 buildings, including coordinating work of subordinates and vendor personnel.
- Standardized documentation to improve network managemen and overall performance with consistent handling of various issues.
- Incorporated feedback from users and new technologies to deliver continuous system improvements.
- Road mapped network changes, including recommending, scheduling, and completing improvements and lifecycle management changes.
- Selected and installed wireless and wired network hardware.
- Kept the network modern and scalable with continuous review and proactive maintenance.
- Managed routine operations, addressed complex issues, and oversaw the planning for potential disasters and the subsequent recovery.
- Defined the network with clear specifications such as charts, equipment configurations and connectivity diagrams.
- Monitored and analyzed network performance and reports on data input or output to detect problems, identify inefficient use of computer resources, or perform capacity planning.
- Selected and deployed platforms, interfaces, bandwidths, or routine schemas to solve network problems.
- Planned for the expected network capacity, setting up the needed infrastructure and access protocols.
- Oversaw network upgrade and expansion projects, including installing equipment and verifying the successful integration of new components.

DIRECTOR OF INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Jemicy School

Baltimore, MD

September 2003 - July 2011

Provide expert oversight and direction to the analysis and implementation of recommendations regarding internal information system environment. Proactively perform various duties, including overseeing daily operations of the department, directly supervising two helpdesk resources, analyzing workflow, determining priorities, implementing standards, and setting deadlines. Manage all phases of systems management, backup, security, and user support systems. Consult and work in

collaboration with users, management, vendors, and technicians concerning technical issues to identify and address computing needs and system requirements. Assess and propose recommendation for improvements to organization's technology use, including hardware and software upgrades. Track and promote computer information resources to facilitate data security and control, strategic execution, and disaster recovery. Effectively manage operational budget and expenditures.

- Consulted with technicians, users, and management to assess computing needs and system requirements.
- Coordinated smooth upgrades to modernize security systems, increasing security and performance.
- Determined feasibility, cost, and resource requirements for any proposed system change.
- Supervised technical support team effectively serving over [Number] users.
- Managed IT team workflows and established priorities, effectively maintaining schedules and consistently meeting objectives.
- Administered \$200,000 yearly budget with minimal waste or excess by carefully controlling expenses and managing procurement.
- Hired and trained well-qualified, tech-savvy staff to keep the department efficient and successful.
- Incorporated new technologies such as Smartboards and other assistive technologies into existing systems.
- Directed and planned installation and maintenance of computer hardware and software.
- Developed greater understanding of virtualization.

SENIOR NETWORK ENGINEER

CIENA Corporation

Baltimore, MD

March 1997 - June 2003

Administered the design and implementation of network LAN and WAN infrastructure for local and worldwide locations. Provided remote access solution for sales and field support personnel. Ensured monthly maintenance of network infrastructure equipment, including switches and routers. Complied with manufacturing managers' guidelines for manufacturing laboratory operations. Cooperated with helpdesk staff in providing end-user support while mentoring other network

engineers. Revamped and modified all LAN switches from Bay to Cisco.

- Responded promptly to out-of-hours emergencies to manage failures affecting critical business systems.
- Road mapped network changes, including recommending, scheduling, and completing improvements and lifecycle management changes.
- Selected and installed wireless and wired network hardware.
- Managed networking needs across 30+ buildings, including coordinating work of subordinates and vendor personnel.
- Handled service calls submitted to help desk to troubleshoot, diagnose, and resolve various network issues.
- Installed and configured equipment to handle needs of 5000+ local and remote users.
- Incorporated feedback from users and new technologies to deliver continuous system improvements.
- Standardized documentation to improve network managemental and overall performance with consistent handling of various issues.
- Controlled user access and passwords with sound network management policies.
- Monitored network performance to identify and correct routin problems and serious concerns.
- Coordinated network or design activities with designers of associated networks.
- Researched, tested, and integrated new hardware and software solutions to meet the network's requirements.
- Oversaw network upgrade and expansion projects, including installing equipment and verifying the successful integration on new components.
- Planned for the expected network capacity, setting up the needed infrastructure and access protocols.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF LIBERAL ARTS: LIBERAL ARTS
Johns Hopkins University
Baltimore, MD

BACHELOR OF ARTS: PHILOSOPHY AND RELIGIOUS STUDIES

Notre Dame of Maryland University Baltimore, MD Graduated Cum Laude